Guide to the Clayton Eshleman Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Clayton Eshleman papers
1935-2015
1990-2015
YCAL MSS 464
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
80.11
(85 boxes)
The collection consists of material created and accumulated by Clayton Eshleman in the course of his activities as a poet, author, translator, and editor, and primarily documents Eshleman's literary career from circa 1992 to 2008 and the publication of Sulfur magazine from circa 1990 to 2000. Material includes notes, drafts, and manuscripts for Eshleman's works of poetry and prose (published after 1994) and for works translated by Eshleman; proofs for issues 28-45/46 of Sulfur, as well as correspondence, unpublished manuscripts, and other production material; correspondence with authors, poets, and colleagues; notebooks; a computer disk; and other papers.
Eshleman, Clayton
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Ken Lopez Bookseller on various funds, 2005, 2009, and 2015. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Boxes 50, 85 (born digital): Restricted fragile materials. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Clayton Eshleman
Clayton Eshleman was born in Indianapolis, Indiana, in 1935. He earned a B.A. in philosophy and an M.A. in creative writing, both from Indiana University. He is the author of numerous collections of poetry and prose, including Under World Arrest (1994), Companion Spider (2002), An Alchemist with One Eye on the Fire (2006), and Reciprocal Distillations (2007), and has translated the work of César Vallejo and Aimé Césaire, among others. He founded and edited the literary magazines Caterpillar (1967-1973) and Sulfur (1981-2000).
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of material created and accumulated by Clayton Eshleman in the course of his activities as a poet, author, translator, and editor, and primarily documents Eshleman's literary career from circa 1992 to 2008 and the publication of Sulfur magazine from circa 1990 to 2000. Material includes notes, drafts, and manuscripts for Eshleman's works of poetry and prose (published after 1994) and for works translated by Eshleman; proofs for issues 28-45/46 of Sulfur, as well as correspondence, unpublished manuscripts, and other production material; correspondence with authors, poets, and colleagues; notebooks; a computer disk; and other papers.
Arrangement
Organized into three groupings: December 2005 Acquisition, June 2009 Acquisition, and July 2015 Acquisition.
Material within this collection has been organized by acquisition reflecting the fact that the collection has been acquired in increments over time.
Researchers should note that material within each acquisition overlaps with and/or relates to material found in other acquisitions. For instance, correspondence and writings can be found in both groupings. In order to locate all relevant material within this collection, researchers will need to consult each acquisition described in the Collection Contents section.
Researchers should also note that similar material can be arranged differently in each acquisition, depending on how the material was organized when it was received by the library.
Sulfur (Pasadena, Calif.); American literature -- 20th Century; American literature -- 21st century; American poetry -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 21st century; Poetry -- Translations into English; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Poets, American -- 21st century -- Archives; Born digital; Electronic documents; Poets; Translators; Eshleman, Clayton
- December 2005 Acquisition, circa 1990-2004; 45.75; (50 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized into five series: Sulfur Production Files; Poetry and Prose; Translations; Correspondence and Subject Files; and Other Papers.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original computer disks are restricted. Copies of electronic files are available through Access Services.
  General note
  Formerly classed as Uncat MSS 836.
  - Sulfur Production Files, circa 1990-2000
    - Issue #28, 5 (Box 1)
    - Issue #29 (Box 1)
    - Issue #30, 9 (Box 1)
    - Issue #31, 2 (Box 1)
    - Issue #31, 4 (Box 2)
    - Issue #32, 7 (Box 2)
    - Issue #33, 4 (Box 2)
    - Issue #33, 6 (Box 3)
    - Issue #34, 4 (Box 3)
    - Issue #36/37, 7 (Box 3)
    - Issue #36/37, 2 (Box 4)
    - Issue #37, 6 (Box 4)
    - Issue #38, 6 (Box 4)
    - Issue #38, 4 (Box 5)
    - Issue #39, 3 (Box 5)
    - Issue #40 + most of another issue, 3 (Box 5)
    - Issue #41, 4 (Box 5)
    - Issue #42, 3 (Box 5)
    - Issue #43, 5 (Box 6)
    - Issue #44, 2 (Box 7)
    - Issue #45/46, 7 (Box 7)
    - Sulfur misc. later issues (Box 7)
    - Sulfur spring 98 and misc., 3 (Box 7)
    - Sulfur spring 97, 3 (Box 7)
    - Sulfur art, photos, negatives, 2 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence A-Fy, 15 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence G-Mf, 17 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence N-West, 18 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence Wet-Z, 2 (Box 11)
    - Sulfur Comes "Mystery File" (Box 11)
    - Sulfur Comes outgoing (Box 11)
    - Correspondence unsorted, 4 (Box 11)
    - Unpublished MSS, 6 (Box 11)
    - Unpublished MSS, 14 (Box 12)
    - Unpublished MSS, 13 (Box 13)
    - Unpublished MSS, 11 (Box 14)
    - Unpublished MSS, 9 (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous material, 6 (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous material, 12 (Box 16)
    - Layout of "Sulfur" covers (Box 17 Oversize)
  - Poetry and Prose
    Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - Companion Spider, circa 2002; 14 (Box 18)
    - Companion Spider, circa 2002; 10 (Box 19)
    - From Scratch, circa 1998; 5 (Box 19)
    - From Scratch, circa 1998; 16 (Box 20)
    - From Scratch, circa 1998; 13 (Box 21)
    - Hades en manganèse (French translation), circa 1998; 4 (Box 21)
    - Juniper Fuse, circa 2003; 4 (Box 22)
    - Juniper Fuse, circa 2003; 15 (Box 23)
    - Juniper Fuse, circa 2003; 11 (Box 24)
    - Juniper Fuse, circa 2003; 15 (Box 25)
    - Juniper Fuse, circa 2003; 15 (Box 26)
    - Juniper Fuse, circa 2003; 2 (Box 27)
    - My Devotion / Erratics, circa 2000, 2004; 11 (Box 27)
    - Under World Arrest, circa 1994; 14 (Box 28)
    - Under World Arrest, circa 1994; 14 (Box 29)
    - Under World Arrest, circa 1994; 11 (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts (poetry), 4 (Box 30)
    - "Materials from Erratics - set aside Sept 15 '99" and other material (Box 30)
    - Worksheets (poetry), 6 (Box 31)
  - Translations
    Arranged alphabetically by author or title.
    - Artaud translation, 9 (Box 31)
    - Notebook of a Return to Native Land by Aimé Césaire, circa 2001 (Box 31)
    - Notebook of a Return to Native Land by Aimé Césaire, circa 2001; 3 (Box 32)
    - Trilce by César Vallejo, circa 1992; 14 (Box 33)
    - Trilce by César Vallejo, circa 1992; 16 (Box 34)
    - "Trilce, Farche, Carman, etc.", 4 (Box 35)
  - Correspondence and Subject Files
    - General Correspondence
      - A-Com, 14 (Box 36)
      - Con-Ge, 13 (Box 37)
      - Gi-Ke, 14 (Box 38)
      - Ke-Ma, 13 (Box 39)
      - Mc-P (cont.), 17 (Box 40)
      - P (cont.)-Sp, 15 (Box 41)
      - S (cont.)-Z, 16 (Box 42)
      - "CE Retained Correspondence", 7 (Box 43)
      - Unsorted correspondence, 13 (Box 44)
    - Correspondence and Subject Files
      - Miraculous Airs (Box 45)
      - Correspondence (Box 45)
      - EMU Materials, 2 (Box 45)
      - 460 Fall 1988 (Box 45)
      - English 335 and 592 (Box 45)
      - Rich 2000 - materials relating to Adrienne Rich's 2000 EMU visit (Box 45)
      - Postcards (Box 45)
      - Correspondence Getneon CE and Adrienne Rich (Box 45)
      - Correspondence CE and Adrienne Rich (Box 45)
      - Adrienne Rich, 4 (Box 45)
      - CAVE Information (Box 45)
      - Cave articles and proposals, destinations article material (Box 45)
      - From Scratch Correspondence (Box 45)
      - Naropa June 2000 (Box 45)
      - Snyder (Box 45)
      - Robert and Kelly letters (Box 45)
      - Women (Box 45)
      - Paul Bahn (Box 45)
      - Creeley (Box 45)
      - Cary Goldstein and J.F. (Box 45)
      - Wolfgang Giegerich correspondence, 2 (Box 45)
      - Kenward Elmslie (Box 46)
      - Weinberger, Eliot (Box 46)
      - Eshleman, circa 1989-1997; 5 (Box 46)
      - Eshleman, 1996-1990; 7 (Box 46)
      - "Auxemery letters", 4 (Box 46)
      - "Auxemery cards" (Box 47)
      - Don Byrd (Box 47)
      - Ferrani Americo (Box 47)
      - Charles Bernstein (Box 47)
      - James Hillman (Box 47)
      - Rachel Blau du Plessis, 2 (Box 47)
      - "Mystery correspondence" (Box 47)
      - Gary Snyder (Box 47)
      - Trilce - translation project, 2 (Box 47)
      - Festival Franco-Anglais (Box 47)
      - Ron Padgett (Box 47)
  - Other Papers
    - Bevis Suit, 6 (Box 48)
    - Cave Tours Literature (Box 48)
    - Correspondence: Cave Tours, 4 (Box 48)
    - Lecture notes late 80s-97 (Box 48)
    - Lecture notes (Box 48)
    - Notebooks, 8 (Box 49)
    - Clayton Eshleman corrected proofs (Box 49)
    - Art Shows, 3 (Box 49)
    - Printed, 2 (Box 49)
    - "1945 from America, A History in Verse Vol. 2 1940-1969," Quark XPress 3.31 figural book font, circa 2000; 1 3.5" floppy disk (59 KB)
      Existence and Location of Copies
      Copies of electronic files are available through Access Services: Disk #20051214-b.0001
  - Computer media
    Box 50 (computer disk): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - 1945 from America, A History in Verse Vol. 2 1940-1969 Quark Xpress 3.31 figural book font, 2005-ycal-1214-b-0001; 1 (Box 50)
      Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
- June 2009 Acquisition, 2003-2008; 10.2; (11 boxes)
  Organized into four series: Poetry and Prose; Translations; Correspondence; and Notebooks.
  Formerly classed as Uncat MSS 1193.
  - Poetry and Prose
    Arranged alphabetically by title of work.
    - "Abyss" / poems from 1989 reworked, 2007; 2 (Box 51)
    - An Alchemist with One Eye on the Fire, circa 2006; 15 (Box 52)
    - Archaic Design, circa 2007; 3 (Box 52)
    - Archaic Design, circa 2007; 17 (Box 53)
    - Everwhat, circa 2003; 2 (Box 53)
    - Everwhat, circa 2003 (Box 54)
    - The Grindstone of Rapport, circa 2008; 15 (Box 54)
    - My Devotion, circa 2004; 3 (Box 54)
    - My Devotion, circa 2004; 10 (Box 55)
    - Reciprocal Distillations, circa 2007; 7 (Box 55)
  - Translations
    - The Complete Poetry of César Vallejo, circa 2007; 23 (Box 56)
    - The Complete Poetry of César Vallejo, circa 2007; 15 (Box 57)
    - Conductors of the Pit, circa 2005; 2 (Box 57)
    - Conductors of the Pit, circa 2005; 8 (Box 58)
  - Correspondence
    Printed email correspondence is arranged alphabetically by surname of correspondent. General correspondence and postcards are arranged in files at the end of the series.
    - Barber, Stephen (Box 58)
    - Bei Dao (Box 58)
    - Berg, Steve (Box 58)
    - Bernstein, Charles (Box 58)
    - Blegvad, Peter (Box 58)
    - Brown, N. O. (Box 58)
    - Chagoya, Enrique (Box 58)
    - Clottes, Jean (Box 58)
    - Cole, Henri (Box 58)
    - Codresco, Andrei (Box 58)
    - Creeley, Robert and Penelope (Box 58)
    - Davis, Wade (Box 58)
    - Ducornet, Rikki (Box 58)
    - DuPlessis, Rachel Blau (Box 58)
    - Eiben, Therese (Box 58)
    - Eshleman, Matthew (Box 58)
    - Gander, Forest (Box 58)
    - Giegerich, Wolfgang (Box 58)
    - Golub, Leon (and Kunce, Samm) (Box 58)
    - Hart, Stephen (Box 58)
    - Hass, Robert (Box 58)
    - Heebner, Mary (Box 58)
    - Hilton, Nelson (Box 58)
    - Hirsch, Edward (Box 58)
    - Hofer, Jen (Box 58)
    - Hoover, Paul (Box 58)
    - Howard, Peter (Box 58)
    - Irvine, Ian and Kroll, Jeri (Box 58)
    - Joron, Andrew (Box 58)
    - Katz, Vincent (Box 58)
    - Kauffman, Janet (Box 58)
    - Kelly, Robert (Box 58)
    - Kendall, Stuart (Box 58)
    - Koshkin, Michael (Box 58)
    - Krukowski, Damon (Box 58)
    - Legros, Jean Paul (Box 58)
    - Levine, Suzanne J. (Box 58)
    - Linh Dinh (Box 58)
    - Maclagan, David (Box 58)
    - McClure, Michael (Box 58)
    - Muldoon, Paul (Box 58)
    - Nutt, Jim (Box 59)
    - Olson, John, 2 (Box 59)
    - Padgett, Ron, 3 (Box 59)
    - Pendell, Dale (Box 59)
    - Phillips, Joe (Box 59)
    - Ranke, Bin (Box 59)
    - Rich, Adrienne, 2 (Box 59)
    - Rothenberg, Jerome (Box 59)
    - Schjeldahl, Peter (Box 59)
    - Schneeman, Carolee (Box 59)
    - Sellers, David (Box 59)
    - Simic, Charles (Box 59)
    - Smith, Dale (Box 59)
    - Snyder, Gary (Box 59)
    - Spears, Andre (Box 59)
    - Tranter, John (Box 59)
    - Vicuna, Cecilia (and James O'Hern) (Box 59)
    - Waldman, Anne (Box 59)
    - Wang Ping (Box 59)
    - Warren, Kenneth (Box 59)
    - Weinberger, Eliot (Box 59)
    - Weiss, Allen (Box 59)
    - Zawacki, Andrew (Box 59)
    - General, 3 (Box 59)
    - General, 11 (Box 60)
    - Postcards, 5 (Box 60)
    - Postcards, 2 (Box 61)
  - Notebooks
    - Notebooks, 13 (Box 61)
- July 2015 Acquisition, 1935-2015; 24.08; (24 boxes)
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Purchased from Ken Lopez Bookseller on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2015.
  Scope and Contents
  This addition consists of writings, correspondence, printed material, teaching materials, artwork, and other papers by or relating to Clayton Eshleman.
  - Anticline, circa 2010; 11 (Box 62)
    Materials relating to the book Anticline, including correspondence, notes, and corrected typescripts.
  - L.A. Weekly clippings, 1983-1984 (Box 63)
  - Notebook of translations of Antonin Artaud, Bernard Bador, Michel Deguy, Robert Marteau, and Guy Etienne, undated (Box 63)
  - The Book of Eternal Death, 1964, 2006 (Box 63)
    Unplublished writings.
  - Confessions of a Luddite, undated (Box 63)
    Unpublished writings.
  - Poetry reading, 2007 (Box 63)
    Introduction and photocopied poems.
  - Review of Robert Tejada's book Mirrors for Gold, 2008 (Box 63)
  - Taffy Martin interview, 1999 (Box 63)
  - American Poetry and the Larger Nature, undated (Box 63)
    Writings with corrections.
  - Translation as Transformational Reading, undated (Box 63)
    Writings with notes and photocopies.
  - Tlazolteotl-Ixcuina, 1967 (Box 63)
    Writings with notes and corrections.
  - Heaven-Bands, 1968-1972 (Box 63)
    An unpublished journal.
  - Curdled Skull, circa 2010 (Box 63)
    Notes for translation of Bernard Bador's writing.
  - Nancy Meets the Momo, 2011 (Box 63)
    Notes and writings from a lecture given about Nancy Spero and Antonin Artaud.
  - Endure, circa 2010 (Box 63)
    Writings, notes, and correspondence relating to Eshleman and Klein's translation of Bei Dao.
  - Correspondence with A. James Arnold concerning the translation of Aime Cesaire's Solar Throat Slashed and the 1939 Notebook of a Return to the Native Land, 2010-2011 (Box 63)
  - Writings, include rejected submissions, notes, and related correspondence and clippings, 1985-2010; 4 (Box 63)
  - The Price of Experience, corrected draft and notes, 2010-2011; 7 (Box 64)
  - Price of Experience and An Anatomy of the Night, 2010-2011; 2 (Box 64)
    Drafts, corrections, and an interview with Jared Demick.
  - Ice-Age lecture related materials, circa 2011 (Box 64)
  - Copies of American Poetry Review, 2006 (Box 64)
  - Erratics, 2010; 2 (Box 64)
    Writings consisting of copies with corrections and highlights and cutouts.
  - An Anatomy of the Night drafts and corrections, 1968-1972, 2004; 2 (Box 64)
  - Interview drafts, 2004-2009 (Box 65)
  - Old contracts, circa 1980s - 2000s (Box 65)
    Correspondence, reciepts and related materials.
  - Contracts and reviews, circa 1960s - 2000s (Box 65)
    Contracts with related materials. Also includes reviews from publications dating back to the 1960s.
  - Solar Throat Slashed, circa 2010; 7 (Box 66)
    Writings, drafts, proofs, correspondenc,e and related materials.
  - Translation of Aime Cesaire 1939 notebook, Return to the Native Land, proof with notes, circa 2012 (Box 66)
  - Under World Arrest, circa 1994 (Box 66)
    Poems not used or revised before publication.
  - Penetralia, 2008-2013 (Box 66)
  - Homuncula: A Jingle, 1990 (Box 66)
    Poem enscribed to Herbert and Virginia from Eshleman.
  - Tavern of the Scarlet Bagpipe, circa 2010
    - Draft with notes, circa 2010 (Box 67)
    - Research, circa 2010 (Box 67)
    - Related writings and drafts, circa 2010; 10 (Box 67)
  - Calendars, 1991-2014 (Box 68)
    Records of daily activities, appointments, and travel.
  - Calendars, 1991-2014 (Box 69)
  - Penetralia, circa 2014; 22 (Box 70)
    Drafts, worksheets, and research materials.
  - Naropa Institute, 2009 (Box 71)
    Teaching material and related correspondence.
  - West Coast reading tour, 2011 (Box 71)
    Correspondence and related materials.
  - Arundel Suit, 1995-2003 (Box 71)
    Legal materials and related correspondence.
  - Adrienne Rich, 2009-2012 (Box 71)
    Printed email correspondence.
  - Herbert Lust, 2009-2014 (Box 71)
    Printed email correspondence and other correspondence with related writings and other materials.
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 2009-2014; 7 (Box 71)
  - Published and unpublished interviews, essays, notes, and reviews., 1960-2014; 17 (Box 72)
    Includes notes on Tejada's Mirrors for Gold, Israeli invasion of the Gaza Strip, for a class What is a Poet?, Leakey's The Origin of Humankind, review of Neruda's The Grapes and the Wind, The Rhinecliff Station, The Color of Time, notes on Avant-Garde for a 2002 panel, notes on Rhisomic Identities", Stages of Regeneration, Talk on Surrealism, Proteus and Poetic Experiment, notes for a talk on contemporary American poetry, and other materials.
  - Miscellaneous writings, 2000-2014 (Box 72)
    Includes correspondence, business papers, translations, and other materials.
  - Reading announcements and programs, 1980-2005; 2 (Box 72)
  - Writings, 2001-2012; 3 (Box 72)
    Pupblished and unpublished writings and related correspondence.
  - Horst Haack artwork and correspondence, 2003-2014 (Box 73)
  - Coils, undated (Box 73)
    Translations
  - Translations, 1983-1995 (Box 73)
    Notes, writings, and copies.
  - Paleolithic cave art project, 1985-2010 (Box 73)
    Research notes and writings.
  - Sakra Boccata, 2013; 2 (Box 73)
    Notebook and annotated copy of Mazzotti's work.
  - Cave art lectures, 2006-2007 (Box 73)
    Notes and photocopies.
  - Tuma interview, 2003 (Box 73)
    Worksheets with notes.
  - Notes, Juniper Fuse project, 1987-2003 (Box 73)
    Draft and notes.
  - Aime Cesaire Conference at Wesleyan, 2013 (Box 73)
    Presentation and talk materials with notes and related correspondence.
  - Unpublished writings, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 73)
    Writings, notes, correspondence, interviews, and other materials.
  - Notebooks, circa 1980s-2010s; 6 (Box 74)
    Notebooks include writings, notes, reminders, and sketches.
  - Juniper Fuse, circa 1970-2000; 2 (Box 75)
    Research materials, notes, and writings.
  - Prehistoric cave art of France, 1980-2009
    - Cave art tours, 1980s (Box 75)
      Writings, travel information, printed ephemera, and related materials.
    - Cave art tours, 1990s; 2 (Box 75)
    - Cave art tours, 2000s; 2 (Box 75)
      Writings, travel information, printed ephemera, and other related materials.
  - Teaching materials, 1986-2008; 13 (Box 76)
    Classroom teaching materials from Eastern Michigan University and University of California Los Angeles.
  - Baby book, 1935 - 1940, undated (Box 76)
    Includes notes and photographs. Also includes an undated drawing depicting jazz titled "Bop."
  - Penetralia, circa 2014; 4 (Box 77)
    Worksheets and notes for poems 1 to 4.
  - Writings, 1972-1994; 2 (Box 77)
    Includes writings, notes, and worksheets for rejected poems, Explanation and Lautreamont Disneyland, Position Paper, Eternity at Domme, Kerlescan, Anticline and An Anatomy of Night, and Tree Grows out of Hell.
  - Ron Padgett, 1986 (Box 77)
    Writings and notes from an article about Padgett published in "Companion Spider."
  - Casenotes, 1991-2003 (Box 77)
    Printed material from Eastern Michigan University.
  - Grant and sabbatical proposals, 1993-2003 (Box 77)
  - Prehistoric cave tours, 1980-2009 (Box 77)
    Notes, schedules, addresses, and related materials.
  - Research material for Juniper Fuse, circa 1978; 6 (Box 78)
  - International Newsletter on Rock Art, 1996-1998 (Box 78)
  - Printed materials used for research
    - Research materials, 1970-2000; 5 (Box 78)
      Articles by archeologists Margaret Conkey, Paul Bahn, Barbara MacLeod, and paleolithic art expert Jean Clottes.
    - Annotated cave art books, 1980-2004; 10 (Box 79)
      Titles include Journey Through the Ice Age, M The Man Who Became Caravaggio, The Creative Explosion, Ten Years Under the Earth, Myth From The Ice Age to Mickey Mouse, The Journal the of Charles Olson Archives, Modernism and Negritude, The Time Falling Bodies Take to Light, October #37, and The Mind in the Cave.
    - Annotated cave art books, 1980-2004; 3 (Box 80)
      Titles include Les Cavernes Du Volp, The Cave of Lascaux: The Final Photographs, and Lascaux or the Birth of Art.
    - Annotated cave art books, 1980-2004; 3 (Box 81)
      Titles include Beyond Art, Secrets of the Ice Age, and The Cave Artists.
    - Other annotated books, 1960-2014; 8 (Box 81)
      Titles include Pan and the Nightmare, The Road to Eleusis, The Cosmic Serpent, Blood Rites, Blood Bread and Roses: How Menstration Created the World, Francis Bacon: Anatomy of An Enigma, The Complete Writings of William Blake, Night Life Night Language, and Sleep and Dreams.
    - Other annotated books, 1959-2014; 13 (Box 82)
      Titles include The Gate of Horn, This Tree Grows Out of Hell, Leaves of Grass, The Murder of Christ, Fearful Symmetry, Love's Body, The Wise Wound: Menstration and Everywoman, The Mass Psychology of Fascism, Inter Views: Conversations with Laura Pozzo, Re-Visioning Psychology, The Dream and the Underworld, The Elegy on Hats, Mirrors for Gold, American Poetry Since 1950: Innovators and Outsiders, Shamanism, The Woman's Encycolpedia of Myths and Secrets, The Collected Poems of Wallace Stevens, The Collected Books of Jack Spicer, and The Discovery of The Orgone: The Function of the Orgasm.
    - Other annotated books, 1968-2014; 6 (Box 83)
      Titles include Leon Golub: Existential Activist and Painter, Brittany, The Maximus Poems, Twins and the Double, and The Maximus Poems: Volume Three, Maximus Poems: I.V., V., VI.
    - Other annotated books, 1975-2003; 4 (Box 84)
      Titles include Healing Fiction, two copies of Ghost Dance: The Origins of Religion, Caravaggion, and The Force of Character and the Lasting Life.
  - Correspondence on flash drive, 2015 (Box 85)
    Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digial files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.